<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title></title><link></link><description></description><language></language><atom:link href="undefinedfeed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><item><title>iOS installing animation</title><description>&lt;p&gt;iOS is full of interesting interaction animations, one of my favorites is the &lt;em&gt;installing&lt;/em&gt; animation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;ve recreated the effect with CSS:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;p data-height=&quot;212&quot; data-theme-id=&quot;0&quot; data-slug-hash=&quot;WQzRLY&quot; data-default-tab=&quot;result&quot; data-user=&quot;timkl&quot; class='codepen'&gt;See the Pen &lt;a href='http://codepen.io/timkl/pen/WQzRLY/'&gt;iOS installing animation&lt;/a&gt; by Tim Kjær Lange (&lt;a href='http://codepen.io/timkl'&gt;@timkl&lt;/a&gt;) on &lt;a href='http://codepen.io'&gt;CodePen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script async src=&quot;//assets.codepen.io/assets/embed/ei.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The approach is inspired by the work of &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/LeaVerou&quot;&gt;Lea Verou&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;#39;m reading her book &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/CSS-Secrets-Solutions-Everyday-Problems/dp/1449372635&quot;&gt;CSS Secrets&lt;/a&gt; at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first part of the animation is achieved by giving a SVG a &lt;code&gt;stroke-width&lt;/code&gt; and then animating the &lt;code&gt;stroke-dasharray&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second part uses a &lt;code&gt;radial-gradient&lt;/code&gt; background with a sudden color-stop. The background is scaled to encompass the entire square.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Invalid Date</pubDate><link>blog/ios-installing-animation.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">blog/ios-installing-animation.html</guid></item><item><title>Lighten &amp; Darken with LESS</title><description>&lt;p&gt;I had a LESS file full of color variables and it looked something like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
@color-blue: #0070b9&lt;br /&gt;
@color-blue-dark: #003b7f&lt;br /&gt;
@color-blue-light: #0079c2&lt;br /&gt;
@color-blue-extra-light: #0080cb&lt;br /&gt;
@color-blue-xx-light: #9ee0ff&lt;br /&gt;
etc.
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My need for additional color tints grew and so did the length of the variable names. Say hi to &lt;code&gt;@color-blue-very-very-light&lt;/code&gt;! There was a another problem: if I wanted to change the hue of &lt;code&gt;@color-blue&lt;/code&gt; I would have to change each and every tint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An unsustainable situation. Today I found out that LESS (and Sass for that matter) has a &lt;code&gt;lighten&lt;/code&gt; and a &lt;code&gt;darken&lt;/code&gt; function. That means that I can have a master color (e.g. &lt;code&gt;@color-blue&lt;/code&gt;) and use &lt;code&gt;lighten&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;darken&lt;/code&gt; to create the tints:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;p data-height=&quot;268&quot; data-theme-id=&quot;0&quot; data-slug-hash=&quot;EjZRwN&quot; data-default-tab=&quot;result&quot; data-user=&quot;timkl&quot; class='codepen'&gt;See the Pen &lt;a href='http://codepen.io/timkl/pen/EjZRwN/'&gt;EjZRwN&lt;/a&gt; by Tim Kjær Lange (&lt;a href='http://codepen.io/timkl'&gt;@timkl&lt;/a&gt;) on &lt;a href='http://codepen.io'&gt;CodePen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;script async src=&quot;//assets.codepen.io/assets/embed/ei.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;</description><pubDate>Invalid Date</pubDate><link>blog/lighten-and-darken-with-less.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">blog/lighten-and-darken-with-less.html</guid></item><item><title>Sweet complexity</title><description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s hypnotic, to watch the guitarist move her hands over the fretboard. It&amp;#39;s been a struggle for her, to achieve this man/machine symbiosis, but it was worth it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vim is a text editor, but it&amp;#39;s not exactly MS Word. To say that Vim has a steep learning curve would be an understatement. Learning Vim is an investment, but it&amp;#39;s an investment that pays fine dividents. Watching a Vim master type is like watching the guitarist pick chords.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As UX Designers we&amp;#39;re all about ease-of-use, but who&amp;#39;s going to invent the &lt;em&gt;complex&lt;/em&gt; tools for tomorrows guitar heroes? Who&amp;#39;s going to invent the next guitar, the next Vim?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#39;m not arguing that complexity is a goal in itself, but neither is limiting complexity where it is needed. &lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Invalid Date</pubDate><link>blog/sweet-complexity.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">blog/sweet-complexity.html</guid></item><item><title>Fischer Random Fun</title><description>&lt;p&gt;In the beginning it&amp;#39;s all play. The designers of games are trying things out - having fun, creating. They invent throw-ins, castling and chequered flags. Slowly the games solidify, status quo creeps in, it&amp;#39;s business as usual. That&amp;#39;s why we can&amp;#39;t have a special rule for diving in the penalty area, where you have to wear a ballerina outfit for the rest of the match.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The traditionalists are against ballerina outfits in football games. They want things to be like the last time we played - it was a 1-1 draw and John fell asleep in front of the TV. In another world 1500 years ago, someone woke up, had breakfast and invented chess. For two weeks chess was soft, like clay - nobody cared about memorizing opening variants. A five year old chess prodigy is reading up on the Sicilian right now, but she would have more fun playing Fischer Random Chess, where the pieces on the first row are shuffled. Pokemon figurine to B4 - checkmate!&lt;/p&gt;
</description><pubDate>Invalid Date</pubDate><link>blog/fischer-random-chess.html</link><guid isPermaLink="true">blog/fischer-random-chess.html</guid></item></channel></rss>